Guide to the Terry Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Terry family papers
1795-1939
MS 482
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(13 boxes)
Papers of five family members, the children and daughter-in-law of Alfred and Clarissa Terry, make up the major part of the collection. The most prominent figure is Alfred Howe Terry, a Civil War general in the Union army, whose correspondence and military papers relate to the Fitz-John Porter case, the Indian campaigns (1870s) and reminiscences of military service and the Civil War. Included are orders for the court martial of General Custer and drawings supposedly given to Terry by Sitting Bull. Other family members include his brother, Adrian, who also served in the Civil War, and Adrian's wife, Isadore Wright Terry, whose correspondence includes letters from her husband during the war describing his experiences.
Terry family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Harriet W. Terry, 1936-1939; diaries of James Terry given by Mrs. C. Sanford Bull, 1956.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series: I. Alfred Howe Terry. II. Adrian Terry. III. Isadore Wright Terry. IV. Harriet Wadsworth Terry. V. Eliza H. Terry. VI.Other Family Members.
Scope and Contents
The Terry Family Papers are organized in six series, with letters placed under the name of the recipient: I. Alfred Howe Terry; II. Adrian Terry; III. Isadore Wright Terry; IV. Harriet Wadsworth Terry. V. Eliza H. Terry; and VI.Other Family Members.
Series I, ALFRED HOWE TERRY, contains papers of the Civil War general. Correspondence consists of letters received and a small amount of outgoing correspondence, including one letter copy book (1885-1887). Prominent topics in the correspondence are Terry's efforts to secure promotion to major general (1880s), the Fitz-John Porter case (1870s), the Indian campaigns (1870s) and reminiscences of military service and the Civil War. Among the important correspondents, there are particularly significant letters from Civil War generals William Tecumseh Sherman, Philip H. Sheridan, Ulysses S. Grant, and Fitz-John Porter. Military Papers includes copies of Terry's military orders and appointments, resolutions of commendation, orders for the court martial of General George A. Custer (1867-1868), and military reports. Personal Papers contains biographical notes, obituaries, photographs, newspapers, and other personal papers.
Series II, ADRIAN TERRY, contains papers relating to the Civil War and other subjects. Correspondence consists primarily of letters from family members and letters from Civil War veterans (1896-1897) responding to his requests for information about the capture of Fort Fisher, N. C. in January, 1865. Civil War Papers includes Adrian Terry's military papers, reports and maps of battles, veterans' association papers, and newspapers. Fort Fisher consists of Terry's reminiscences and historical accounts of the battle, articles by others, copies of military reports, maps, notes, and newspaper articles. Personal Papers contains biographical notes, Yale College materials, a copy of memorial resolutions on Adrian Terry's death, and miscellaneous papers of biographical interest.
Series III, ISADORE (WRIGHT) TERRY, consists of papers of Adrian Terry's wife. Correspondence contains letters from several relatives and friends, including her grandmother, Frances (Smith) Cowles, and her sister, Frances Wright. Adrian Terry's letters to his wife during the Civil War provide a valuable personal perspective on the war. Personal Papers consists of invitations, calling cards, children's hair, and photographs.
Series IV, HARRIET W. TERRY, contains letters received by Harriet Wadsworth Terry (1830-1908) and a small amount of personal papers. Most of the Correspondence is from family members and relatives, including Robert P. Hughes, Alfred Howe Terry, and Adrian Terry. Other correspondents include friends of Alfred Howe Terry - such as Joseph R. Hawley; George Grant MacCurdy, William Tecumseh Sherman, and W. W. Witherspoon - many of whom sent condolences after Terry's death in 1890. Personal Papers contains resolutions on her resignation from Vassar College and miscellaneous manuscripts.
Series V, ELIZA H. TERRY, contains letters received and a diary by Eliza Howe Terry. Correspondence consists entirely of letters from her brothers and sisters, particularly Alfred Howe Terry. The Diary (1875 Jul) describes her ocean voyage to Europe.
Series VI, OTHER FAMILY MEMBERS, consists of papers of other members of the Terry family. These include relatives in the Brinley, Cates, Cowles, Howe, Hughes, Terry, Wadsworth, Whittlesey, and Wright families. In addition to genealogical material, there are papers of many individual family members, including Alfred Terry, Clarissa (Howe) Terry, and their children, Clara H. (Terry) Hughes, Frances Terry, Jeremiah Wadsworth Terry, and Robert Goldsborough Terry. There are also papers of Clarissa (Howe) Terry's father, Hezekiah Howe; Clara H. (Terry) Hughes's husband, Robert Patterson Hughes; Isadore (Wright) Terry's father, Albert A. Wright, and her sister, Sarah Wright. The children of Adrian and Isadore (Wright) Terry are also represented: Clarissa Howe (Terry) Cates, Alfred Howe Terry (1875-1965), and Harriet W. Terry. The papers of James Terry (1823-1870) consist of correspondence from 1855 to 1869. The most extensive group of materials in this series is the diaries, 1875-1912, and other papers of James Terry (1844-1919).
Biographical / Historical
Adrian Terry (1831-1906): businessman; officer in the Union Army, 1861-1864; chief engineer, Knoxville and Kentucky Railroad, 1866-1869.
Custodial History
The Terry Family Papers were given to Yale University Library in 1936-1939 by Miss Harriet W. Terry, daughter of Adrian and Isadore (Wright) Terry. The diaries of James Terry (1844-1919) were given by Mrs. C. Sanford Bull. When the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library was built, part of the Terry papers were transferred there and another part remained in Manuscripts and Archives. These two groups of papers were combined in 1978, when processing of the collection began.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Anthropology; Armed Forces; Cholera; Families; Fort Fisher (N.C.: Fort) -- Siege, 1864-1865; Indians of North America; Medicine; Shipping; Women; Kansas -- Description and travel; United States -- Description and travel; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Diaries; Soldiers; Sitting Bull, 1831-1890; Aiken, William Appleton, 1833-1929; Armstrong, S. C. (Samuel Chapman), 1839-1893; Bacon, Alfred Terry; Bacon, Alice Mabel, 1858-1918; Bacon, Catherine E. Terry; Bacon, Thomas R.; Barnes, N.S.; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943; Birge, Henry Warner, 1825-1888; Bradley, Luther Prentice, 1822-1910; Brinley, Frances Ellen Terry, 1816-1876; Brinley, George P.; Cates, Clarissa Howe Terry; Comstock, C. B. (Cyrus Ballou), 1831-1910; Cooke, Rose Terry, 1827-1892; Cowles, Frances Smith; Crane, Charles Henry, 1825-1883; Curtis, Newton Martin, 1835-1910; Custer, George A. (George Armstrong), 1839-1876; Farrington, Daniel Summer; Gardiner, Asa Bird, 1839-1919; Goodsell, Abby F.; Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885; Graves, Charles Hinman, 1839-1928; Greenleaf, Charles R. (Charles Ravenscroft), 1838-1911; Hawley, Joseph R. (Joseph Roswell), 1826-1905; Hazen, William Babcock, 1830-1887; Hoar, George Frisbie, 1826-1904; Howe, Henry, 1816-1893; Hughes, Clara Henrietta Terry, 1835-1891; Hughes, Robert Patterson, 1839-1909; Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1853-1937; Jones, E. W.; Jones, John R.; Landers, William E.; Lossing, Benson John, 1813-1891; Lossing, Helen Sweet, -1912; Lull, Edward Phelps, 1836-1887; MacCurdy, George Grant, 1863-1947; Maginnis, Martin, 1841-1919; McClung, M.C.; McGuffey, Charles D.; McIlvaine, Charles, 1840-1909; Meigs, Montgomery, 1847-1931; Mordecai, Alfred, 1840-1904; Morris, Dwight; Morris, J. F.; Osborn, Francis Augustus, 1833-1914; Pennypacker, Galusha, 1844-1916; Pierpont, William H.; Platt, Orville Hitchcock, 1827-1905; Porter, Fitz-John, 1822-1901; Porter, Sarah, 1813-1900; Price, Kenneth; Prince, Frederick W.; Ramsey, Alexander, 1815-1903; Randlett, James F.; Raymond, John H. (John Howard), 1814-1878; Rockwell, Alfred Perkins, 1834-1903; Sanford, Edward J.; Sanford, Emma J.; Schofield, John McAllister, 1831-1906; Sheridan, Philip Henry, 1831-1888; Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891; Stanton, Edwin M. (Edwin McMasters), 1814-1869; Strieby, Michael Epahras, 1815-1896; Summers, John Edward, 1822-; Terry, Adrian, 1831-1906; Terry, Alfred Howe, 1827-1890; Terry, Alfred Howe, 1875-1965; Terry, Clarissa Howe, d. 1874; Terry, Eliza Howe, 1840-; Terry, Frances, 1843-; Terry, Harriet Wadsworth, 1830-1908; Terry, Isadore Lee Wright; Terry, James, 1823-1870; Terry, James, 1844-1919; Terry, Jane Russell, 1846-; Terry, Jeremiah Wadsworth, 1833-1905; Terry, Josephine; Terry, Kate W.; Terry, Luther; Terry, Marion S.; Terry, Robert Goldsborough, 1837-1878; Thompson, Texas Ben, 1842-1884; Thompson, John; Thomson, Frank, 1841-1899; Tourtellotte, John E. (John Everett), 1869-1939; Towle, George F.; Trumbull, H. Clay (Henry Clay), 1830-1903; Wayland, H. L. (Heman Lincoln), 1830-1898; Whittlesey, Elisha, 1783-1863; Witherspoon, W.W.; Woodbury, R.W.; Wright, Albert A. (Albert Allen), 1846-1905; Wright, Frances; Wright, Julius A.; Wright, Samuel; Wright, Sarah; Zent, Samuel S.; Terry family; American Museum of Natural History; Vassar College; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1852; Yale University -- Students
- Alfred Howe Terry, 1861-1911; Series I; .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender, with letters arranged chronologically within each folder. Military Papers and Personal Papers are arranged by type of material, in roughly chronological order.
  - Correspondence
    - Aiken, William Appleton, 1833-1884 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Armstrong, Samuel Chapman, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Barnes, N. S., 1881 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Benét, S. V., 1881 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Birge, Henry Warner, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bradley, Luther P., 1883 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Brinley, George P., 1882 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cooke, Rose (Terry), 1889 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Crane, C. H., 1881 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Farrington, Daniel Summer, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Gardiner, Asa Bird, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Grant, Ulysses Simpson, 1882-1885 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Hazen, William Babcock, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hoar, George Frisbie, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Howe, Henry, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Hughes, Clara H. (Terry), 1878 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Jones, John R., 1890 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Lull, Edward P., 1886 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Maginnis, Martin, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Meigs, Montgomery C., 1883 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Mordecai, Alfred, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Morris, Dwight, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Osborn, Francis A., 1882 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Platt, Orville Hitchcock, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Porter, Fitz-John, 1882-1888 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Price, Kenneth, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Ramsey, Alexander, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Schofield, John McAllister, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Sheridan, Philip Henry, 1875-1883 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Sherman, William Tecumseh, 1875-1886 (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
    - Stanton, Edwin McMasters, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Strieby, Michael E., 1882 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Summers, John E., 1881 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Terry, Adrian, 1864-1886 (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
    - Terry, Eliza Howe, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Terry, Harriet Wadsworth, 1865-1885, undated (Box 1, Folder 38-40)
    - Terry, Isadore Lee (Wright), 1883-1885 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Terry, Robert Goldsborough, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Thompson, Benjamin, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Thomson, Frank, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Trumbull, Henry Clay, 1866-1887 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Wayland, H. L., 1886-1887 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1879-1885, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Letter copy book, 1885-1887 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Military Papers
    - Military orders and appointments, 1861-1867 (Box 2, Folder 49-50)
    - Resolutions commending Gen. Alfred Howe Terry, 1865, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Court Martial orders for General George A. Custer, 1867-1868 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Report on reorganization of the Army, by A. H. Terry, 1878 November 11 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Reports of military investigation, 1878, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Personal Papers
    - Biographical notes, by Harriet W. Terry, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Drawings given to A. H. Terry by Sitting Bull (?), [c. 1876?] (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Military Order of the Loyal Legion of the United States, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - American Geographical Society, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - The New South (Port Royal, S.C.), 1862, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Obituaries and memorial notices, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Newspaper obituaries, 1890 December (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Newspaper memorial tributes, 1890-1911 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Biographical article: The National Encyclopedia of American Biography (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Newsclippings, 1862-1890, undated (Box 2, Folder 65-67)
- Adrian Terry, 1842-1906; Series II; 1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender, with letters arranged chronologically within each folder. Civil War Papers, Fort Fisher, and Personal Papers are organized by type of material.
  - Correspondence
    - Brinley, George P., 1861 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Comstock, Cyrus Ballou, 1896-1897 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Curtis, Newton Martin, 1896-1897 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Graves, Charles H., 1896-1897 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Hawley, Joseph R., 1896 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Hughes, Robert Patterson, 1891-1897 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
    - Landers, William E., 1896 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Pennypacker, Galusha, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Pierpont, William H., 1896-1897 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Prince, Frederick W. [Gatling Gun Company], 1897 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Randlett, James F., 1865-1896 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Rockwell, Alfred P., 1898 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Sanford, Edward J., 1862-1866 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Terry, Alfred Howe (1827-1890), 1866-1888, undated (Box 3, Folder 15-17)
    - Terry, Alfred Howe (1875-1965), 1896-1903 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Terry, Clarissa (Howe), 1861-1876, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Terry, Frances, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Terry, Harriet Wadsworth, 1861-1903 (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
    - Terry, Isadore Lee (Wright)
      - 1860 August - 1862, 1865, 1879, undated (Box 3, Folder 23-26)
    - Terry, Jane Russell, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Terry, Jeremiah Wadsworth, 1863-1897 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
    - Terry, Luther, 1896-1897 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Terry, Robert Goldsborough, 1865-1866 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Thompson, John, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Towle, George F., 1896-1897 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Woodbury, R. W., 1897 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Wright, Albert A. Wright, Frances, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Zent, Samuel M., 1896 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - General correspondence
      - A-K (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - L-Z (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Unidentified (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1842, 1896, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Civil War Papers
    - Military orders and appointments, 1862-1866 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Invitation and program for Thanksgiving festival, Fort Pulaski, Georgia, 1862 November (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Military passes, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - List of prisoners captured near Charleston, South Carolina, 1863 July-August (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Military reports of battles, 1864 May-October (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Maps of Petersburg, Virginia, and Pocotalico, South Carolina, 1864, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Payroll records, 1883-1885 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Veterans' associations papers, 1887-1902 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Poems by Rose Terry and Charles G. Halpine, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Newspapers, 1860-1863, 1866 (Box 4, Folder 50-51)
  - Fort Fisher
    - Adrian Terry, "Blockade Running & Its Death Blow at Wilmington, N.C. with the two Expeditions against Fort Fisher" (bound AMs) (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Adrian Terry, "Wilmington and Fort Fisher" (bound AMs, two drafts) (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Adrian Terry, "The Capture of Fort Fisher" (AMs drafts of several versions) (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Adrian Terry, "Three Days at Fort Fisher" (AMs drafts) (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Adrian Terry, "Comments on Gen. Ames Account of Capture of Fort Fisher" (Ams), Circa 1897 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Adelbert Ames, "The Capture of Fort Fisher, North Carolina" (pamphlet), 1897 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Edgar Ketchum, "Personal Reminiscences of the Capture of Fort Fisher and Wilmington, North Carolina," The United Service, 1896 December (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Notes: copies of military reports (Box 5, Folder 59-60)
    - Notes (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Maps of Fort Fisher and Wilmington, 1864-1865 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Newspaper reports of Fort Fisher expedition, 1865 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Newspaper articles, 1891-1897 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Personal Papers
    - Biographical notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Yale College examination questions and Class of 1852 circular letter, 1852, 1863 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Diploma from "Boatclubum Transitorium," New Haven, Connecticut, 1854 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Invitations and calling cards, 1866-1867, undated (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Resolutions on death of Adrian Terry, by the Director of the East Tennessee National Bank, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1842-1874, undated (Box 5, Folder 70)
- Isadore (Wright) Terry, 1853-1896; Series III; .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender, with letters arranged chronologically within each folder. Personal Papers is arranged by type of material.
  - Correspondence
    - Brinley, Frances Ellen (Terry), 1861 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Cowles, Frances (Smith), 1853-1867, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Hughes, Clara H. (Terry), 1865 January-February (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Jones, E. W., 1859 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - McClung, M. C., 1860 May 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - McGuffey, Charles D., 1896 September 17 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Sanford, Emma J., 1862, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Smith, D., 1861 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Terry, Adrian
      - 1860-1871, 1873-1879 (Box 6, Folder 8-27)
      - 1882-1894 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Terry, Alfred Howe, 1881-1887, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - Terry, Clarissa (Howe), 1860-1866, undated (Box 7, Folder 31-32)
      - Terry, Harriet Wadsworth, 1860-1862 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - Whittlesey, Elisha, 1853-1860 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - Wright, Frances, 1855-1856, undated (Box 7, Folder 35-36)
    - Wright, Julius A., 1896, October 25 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Wright, Mrs. Pitkin C., 1896 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Wright, Samuel, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Unidentified (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Personal Papers
    - Invitations and calling cards, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Photographs of children, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Children's hair, 1863-1873 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Harriet W. Terry, (1861-1909); Series IV; 0.5; (1 box)
  - Correspondence
    - Bacon, Alfred Terry, 1890 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Bacon, Alice Mabel, 1890-1905 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bacon, Catherine E. (Terry), 1875 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bacon, Thomas R., 1890 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Brinley, Frances Ellen (Terry), 1865, 1871 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Cooke, Rose (Terry), 1889-1890 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Goodsell, Abby F., 1877-1890 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Greenleaf, Charles R., 1890 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Hawley, Joseph R., 1901 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Hughes, Clara H. (Terry), 1863-1888 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Hughes, Robert Patterson, 1891-1909 (Box 8, Folder 11-13)
    - Lossing, Benson J., 1877-1878 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Lossing, Helen S. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - MacCurdy, George Grant, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - McIlvaine, Charles, 1890 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Morris, J. F., 1891 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Porter, Sarah, 1865-1890 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Raymond, John Howard, 1871-1874 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Sherman, William Tecumseh, 1890 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Terry, Adrian, 1862-1889 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Terry, Alfred Howe (1827-1890)
      - 1861-1864, 1874, 1876, 1877-1887, undated (Box 8, Folder 22-25)
    - Terry, Alfred Howe (1875-1965), 1879-1880 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Terry, Clarissa (Howe), 1872 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Terry, Eliza Howe, 1888 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Terry, Frances, 1876 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Terry, Jane Russell, 1873-1879, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Terry, Jeremiah Wadsworth, 1863, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Terry, Kate W., 1890 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Terry, Marion S., 1890 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Terry, Robert Goldsborough, 1876 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Tourtellotte, J. E., 1890 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Witherspoon, W. W., 1909 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - General correspondence
      - A-G, 1890-1909 (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - H-Z, 1865-1907 (Box 8, Folder 38)
      - Unidentified, 1880-1903 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1878-1901 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Personal Papers
    - Resolutions on her resignation from Vassar College, 1877-1878 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 8, Folder 42)
- Eliza H. Terry, 1862-1889; Series V; 0.25; (1 box)
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender, with letters arranged chronologically within each folder.
  - Correspondence
    - Hughes, Clara H. T., 1884 March 30 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Terry, Adrian, [1889?] (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Terry, Alfred Howe
      - 1862-1872, 1875-1885 (Box 9, Folder 3-8)
    - Terry, Harriet Wadsworth, 1878-1879 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Diary
    - 1875 July (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Other Family Members, 1795-1939; Series VI; 1.75 linear feet (4 boxes)
  This series is organized alphabetically by name of the individual whose papers are included. Under each name, papers arranged by type of material. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender (if more than one folder), or chronologically.
  - Brinley, Frances Ellen (Terry): newsclippings, 1883, 1894 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Cates, Clarissa Howe (Terry)
    - Correspondence: Terry, Adrian, 1879-1894 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Terry, Alfred Howe, 1882 March (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Terry, Harriet W., 1878 August (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Genealogy, obituary, 1905, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Cowles Family: genealogy, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Cowles, David Smith: obituary, 1863 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Cowles, Rev. Pitkin: sermon, 1823 February 19 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Howe, Hezekiah
    - Military orders, 1814 September 6 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Estate papers, genealogy, 1796-1797, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "William Beaumont's Letter to … Hezekiah Howe [1834]", 1933 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Howe, Sarah: estate papers, 1799-1839 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Hughes, Clara H. (Terry)
    - Correspondence: Terry, Alfred Howe, 1862 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Terry, Harriet W., 1862 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Scrapbook: leaves from Civil War battlefields, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Hughes, Robert Patterson
    - Correspondence, 1890-1909 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Article about Bergamon, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)